<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Atomic Habits - 标签 - 林风's Blog</title><link>https://leoxiewl.github.io/tags/atomic-habits/</link><description>Atomic Habits - 标签 - 林风's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>zh-CN</language><copyright>林风的博客</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://leoxiewl.github.io/tags/atomic-habits/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>day09 The Best Way to Start a New Habit</title><link>https://leoxiewl.github.io/day09-atomic-habits/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>xxxx</author><guid>https://leoxiewl.github.io/day09-atomic-habits/</guid><description><![CDATA[<ol>
<li><strong>implementation intention</strong></li>
</ol>
<p>Implementation intention , which is a plan you make beforehand about when and where to act.</p>
<p>Broadly speaking, the format for creating an implementation intention is:</p>
<p><strong>“When situation X arises, I will perform response Y.”</strong></p>
<p>eg. Writing down the exact time to read books.</p>
<p>When the moment of action occurs, there is no need to make a decision. Simply follow your predetermined plan.</p>
<p>The simple way to apply this strategy to your habits is to fill out this sentence:</p>]]></description></item><item><title>day08 Be aware of your habits and actions, then point it</title><link>https://leoxiewl.github.io/day08-atomic-habits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>xxxx</author><guid>https://leoxiewl.github.io/day08-atomic-habits/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>With enough practice, your brain will pick up on the cues that predict certain outcomes without consciously thinking about it.This is what makes habits useful.</p>
<p>It’s also what makes them dangerous. As habits form, your actions come under the direction of your automatic and nonconscious mind. You fall into old patterns before you realize what’s happening</p>
<p><strong>Solution</strong></p>
<p><strong>Always be aware of your bad habits. Before you engage in these habits, say out loud, &lsquo;What am I about to do and what will be the consequences?</strong></p>]]></description></item><item><title>day07 Chapter 3 Summary</title><link>https://leoxiewl.github.io/day07-atomic-habits-summary/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>xxxx</author><guid>https://leoxiewl.github.io/day07-atomic-habits-summary/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>A habit is a behavior that has been repeated enough times to become automatic.</p>
<p>The ultimate purpose of habits is to solve the problems of life with as little energy and effort as possible.</p>
<p>Any habit can be broken down into a feedback loop that involves four steps: cue, craving, response, and reward.</p>
<p>The Four Laws of Behavior Change are a simple set of rules we can use to build better habits. They are (1) make it obvious, (2) make it attractive, (3) make it easy, and (4) make it satisfying.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>day07 Use four steps to design habits</title><link>https://leoxiewl.github.io/day07-atomic-habits/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>xxxx</author><guid>https://leoxiewl.github.io/day07-atomic-habits/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>we need to transform these four steps into a practical framework that we can use to design good habits and eliminate bad ones.</p>
<h2 id="how-to-create-a-good-habit">How to Create a Good Habit</h2>
<p>The 1st law (Cue): Make it obvious.</p>
<p>The 2nd law (Craving): Make it attractive.</p>
<p>The 3rd law (Response): Make it easy.</p>
<p>The 4th law (Reward): Make it satisfying.</p>
<h2 id="how-to-break-a-bad-habit">How to Break a Bad Habit</h2>
<p>Inversion of the 1st law (Cue): Make it invisible.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>day06 4 Simple Steps to Build Better Habits</title><link>https://leoxiewl.github.io/day06-atomic-habits-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>xxxx</author><guid>https://leoxiewl.github.io/day06-atomic-habits-2/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p><strong>WHY YOUR BRAIN BUILDS HABITS</strong></p>
<p>A habit is a behavior that has been repeated enough times to become automatic.</p>
<p>There is the feedback loop behind all human behavior: try, fail, learn, try differently</p>
<p><strong>THE HABIT LOOP</strong></p>


<ol>
<li>cue-提示</li>
<li>craving-渴求</li>
<li>reward-反应</li>
<li>response-奖励</li>
</ol>
<p>First, there is the <strong>cue</strong>. The cue triggers your brain to initiate a behavior.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>day06 Chapter 2 Summary</title><link>https://leoxiewl.github.io/day06-atomic-habits/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>xxxx</author><guid>https://leoxiewl.github.io/day06-atomic-habits/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>There are three levels of change: outcome change, process change,and identity change.The most effective way to change your habits is to focus not on what you want to achieve, but on who you wish to become.</p>
<p>Your identity emerges out of your habits. Every action is a vote for the type of person you wish to become.</p>
<p>Becoming the best version of yourself requires you to continuously edit your beliefs, and to upgrade and expand your identity.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>day05 Chapter 1 Summary</title><link>https://leoxiewl.github.io/day05-atomic-habits/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>xxxx</author><guid>https://leoxiewl.github.io/day05-atomic-habits/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Habits are the compound interest of self-improvement. Getting 1 percent better every day counts for a lot in the long-run.</p>
<p>Habits are a double-edged sword. They can work for you or against you, which is why understanding the details is essential.</p>
<p>Small changes often appear to make no difference until you cross a critical threshold.The most powerful outcomes of any compounding process are delayed. You need to be patient.</p>
<p>An atomic habit is a little habit that is part of a larger system. Just as atoms are the building blocks of molecules, atomic habits are the building blocks of remarkable results.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>day05 The most importantly, What is your identity.</title><link>https://leoxiewl.github.io/day05-atomic-habits-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>xxxx</author><guid>https://leoxiewl.github.io/day05-atomic-habits-2/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>THREE LAYERS OF BEHAVIOR CHANGE
</p>
<p>结果：The first layer is changing your outcome. &mdash; losing weight, publishing a book, winning a championship.</p>
<p>行动：The second layer is changing your process. &mdash; developing a meditation practice</p>
<p>角色：The third and deepest layer is changing your identity. &mdash; your worldview, your self-image</p>
<p><strong>Outcomes are about what you get. Processes are about what you do. Identity is about what you believe</strong></p>]]></description></item><item><title>day04 FORGET ABOUT GOALS, FOCUS ON SYSTEMS INSTEAD</title><link>https://leoxiewl.github.io/day04-atomic-habits/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>xxxx</author><guid>https://leoxiewl.github.io/day04-atomic-habits/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Imagine that you have an ice cube sitting on the table in front of you.</p>
<p>The room is cold and you can see your breath. It is currently twenty-five degrees.</p>
<p>Ever so slowly, the room begins to heat up.</p>
<p>Twenty-six degrees.</p>
<p>Twenty-seven.</p>
<p>Twenty-eight.</p>
<p>The ice cube is still sitting on the table in front of you.</p>
<p>Twenty-nine degrees.</p>
<p>Thirty.</p>
<p>Thirty-one.</p>
<p>Still, nothing has happened.</p>
<p>Then, thirty-two degrees.</p>
<p>The ice begins to melt. A one-degree shift,seemingly no different from the temperature increases before it, has unlocked a huge change.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>day03 Your future depends on what you do now</title><link>https://leoxiewl.github.io/day03-atomic-habits/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>xxxx</author><guid>https://leoxiewl.github.io/day03-atomic-habits/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Habits are the compound interest of self-improvement.</p>
<p>习惯是自我提升的复利</p>
<p>They seem to make little difference on any given way and yet the impact they deliver over the months and years can be enormous.</p>
<p>他们在一天内看不到什么区别，但是几个月几年时间的积累产生的影响可能是巨大的。</p>]]></description></item></channel></rss>