<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>English Daily on 林风's Blog</title><link>https://leoxiewl.github.io/english-daily/</link><description>Recent content in English Daily on 林风's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>zh-cn</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://leoxiewl.github.io/english-daily/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>day03 Your future depends on what you do now</title><link>https://leoxiewl.github.io/2024/01/16/day03-atomic-habits/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://leoxiewl.github.io/2024/01/16/day03-atomic-habits/</guid><description>&lt;p>Habits are the compound interest of self-improvement.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>习惯是自我提升的复利&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They seem to make little difference on any given way and yet the impact they deliver over the months and years can be enormous.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>他们在一天内看不到什么区别，但是几个月几年时间的积累产生的影响可能是巨大的。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We often dismiss small changes because they don’t seem to matter very much in the moment. If you save a little money now, you’re still not a millionaire. If you go to the gym three days in a row, you’re still out of shape. If you study Mandarin for an hour tonight, you still haven’t learned the language. We make a few changes, but the results never seem to come quickly and so we slide back into our previous routines.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>我们经常忽略一些小的变化，因为它看起来没有那么重要。如果你现在省了一些钱，你不会是百万富翁。如果你去了三天健身房，你的身材仍旧走样。你一晚上学了一个小时普通话，还是不会这门语言。我们做了一些改变，但是结果并没有那么快来，所以我们又像往常一样。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A slight change in your daily habits can guide your life to a very different destination.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That said, it doesn’t matter how successful or unsuccessful you are right now. What matters is whether your habits are putting you on the path toward success.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>无所谓现在成不成功，重要的是你的习惯是否让你在通往成功的路上。&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>day02 1% better every day</title><link>https://leoxiewl.github.io/2024/01/15/day02-atomic-habits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://leoxiewl.github.io/2024/01/15/day02-atomic-habits/</guid><description>&lt;p>1% worse every day for one year. 0.99^365 = 00.03&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1% better every day for one year. 1.01^365 = 37.78&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://res.weread.qq.com/wrepub/CB_GbJ1U11UZEV96i36gZ6nmEpt_Image00004.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Photo by 1% worse and 1% better"
>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>day01 minor remarkable</title><link>https://leoxiewl.github.io/2024/01/14/day01-atomic-habits/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://leoxiewl.github.io/2024/01/14/day01-atomic-habits/</guid><description>&lt;p>Changes that seem small and unimportant at first will compound remarkable results if you are willing to stick with them for years. The pieces of things that are minor, but give you a sense of control over your life and you feel confident.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>