<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>English Daily on 林风's Blog</title><link>https://leoxiewl.github.io/english-daily/</link><description>Recent content in English Daily on 林风's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>zh-cn</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://leoxiewl.github.io/english-daily/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>day10</title><link>https://leoxiewl.github.io/2024/10/01/day10-the-algebra-of-wealth/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://leoxiewl.github.io/2024/10/01/day10-the-algebra-of-wealth/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>财富 = 专注 + (stoicism自律 x 时间 x 多样化)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>This is the first lesson in this book: economic security isn’t a function of what you earn but what you keep and knowing how much is enough for you.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>这本书的第一课，财富自由不是你能够赚多少钱而是你能够存多少钱并且知道有多少钱对你来说是足够的。&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>财富自由 = 被动收入 &amp;gt; 日常支出&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>day09 The Best Way to Start a New Habit</title><link>https://leoxiewl.github.io/2024/01/23/day09-atomic-habits/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://leoxiewl.github.io/2024/01/23/day09-atomic-habits/</guid><description>&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>implementation intention&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Implementation intention , which is a plan you make beforehand about when and where to act.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Broadly speaking, the format for creating an implementation intention is:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>“When situation X arises, I will perform response Y.”&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>eg. Writing down the exact time to read books.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When the moment of action occurs, there is no need to make a decision. Simply follow your predetermined plan.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The simple way to apply this strategy to your habits is to fill out this sentence:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>I will [BEHAVIOR] at [TIME] in [LOCATION].&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you aren’t sure when to start your habit, try the first day of the week,month, or year&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="2">
&lt;li>habit stacking&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>day08 Be aware of your habits and actions, then point it</title><link>https://leoxiewl.github.io/2024/01/22/day08-atomic-habits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://leoxiewl.github.io/2024/01/22/day08-atomic-habits/</guid><description>&lt;p>With enough practice, your brain will pick up on the cues that predict certain outcomes without consciously thinking about it.This is what makes habits useful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s also what makes them dangerous. As habits form, your actions come under the direction of your automatic and nonconscious mind. You fall into old patterns before you realize what’s happening&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Solution&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Always be aware of your bad habits. Before you engage in these habits, say out loud, &amp;lsquo;What am I about to do and what will be the consequences?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That’s the origin of the &lt;strong>Habits Scorecard&lt;/strong>, which is a simple exercise you can use to become more aware of your behavior.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>create your own, make a list of your daily habits.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Wake up&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Turn off alarm&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Check my phone&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Go to the bathroom&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Weigh myself&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Take a shower&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Brush my teeth&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="2">
&lt;li>write “+”, write “–” or write “=”&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Once you have a full list, look at each behavior, and ask yourself, “Is this a good habit, a bad habit, or a neutral habit?” If it is a good habit, write “+” next to it. If it is a bad habit, write “–”. If it is a neutral habit, write “=”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The marks you give to a particular habit will depend on your situation and your goals.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>There are no good habits or bad habits. There are only effective habits. That is,effective at solving problems&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Smoking a cigarette may reduce stress right now (that’s how it’s serving you), but it’s not a healthy long-term behavior.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ol start="3">
&lt;li>Ask yourself questions.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Does this behavior help me become the type of person I wish to be? Does this habit cast a vote for or against my desired identity?”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>day07 Chapter 3 Summary</title><link>https://leoxiewl.github.io/2024/01/20/day07-atomic-habits-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://leoxiewl.github.io/2024/01/20/day07-atomic-habits-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>A habit is a behavior that has been repeated enough times to become automatic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The ultimate purpose of habits is to solve the problems of life with as little energy and effort as possible.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Any habit can be broken down into a feedback loop that involves four steps: cue, craving, response, and reward.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Four Laws of Behavior Change are a simple set of rules we can use to build better habits. They are (1) make it obvious, (2) make it attractive, (3) make it easy, and (4) make it satisfying.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>day07 Use four steps to design habits</title><link>https://leoxiewl.github.io/2024/01/20/day07-atomic-habits/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://leoxiewl.github.io/2024/01/20/day07-atomic-habits/</guid><description>&lt;p>we need to transform these four steps into a practical framework that we can use to design good habits and eliminate bad ones.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-create-a-good-habit">How to Create a Good Habit&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The 1st law (Cue): Make it obvious.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The 2nd law (Craving): Make it attractive.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The 3rd law (Response): Make it easy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The 4th law (Reward): Make it satisfying.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-break-a-bad-habit">How to Break a Bad Habit&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Inversion of the 1st law (Cue): Make it invisible.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Inversion of the 2nd law (Craving): Make it unattractive.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Inversion of the 3rd law (Response): Make it difficult.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Inversion of the 4th law (Reward): Make it unsatisfying.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>day06 4 Simple Steps to Build Better Habits</title><link>https://leoxiewl.github.io/2024/01/19/day06-atomic-habits-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://leoxiewl.github.io/2024/01/19/day06-atomic-habits-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>WHY YOUR BRAIN BUILDS HABITS&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A habit is a behavior that has been repeated enough times to become automatic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is the feedback loop behind all human behavior: try, fail, learn, try differently&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>THE HABIT LOOP&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="day06-atomic-habits-2.assets/CB_GbJ1U11UZEV96i36gZ6nmEpt_Image00010.jpg" alt="img" style="zoom: 15%;" />
&lt;img src="https://pic.imgdb.cn/item/65aa196c871b83018ad4f035.jpg" style="zoom: 25%;" />
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>cue-提示&lt;/li>
&lt;li>craving-渴求&lt;/li>
&lt;li>reward-反应&lt;/li>
&lt;li>response-奖励&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>First, there is the &lt;strong>cue&lt;/strong>. The cue triggers your brain to initiate a behavior.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our prehistoric ancestors were paying attention to cues that signaled the location of primary rewards like &lt;strong>food, water, and sex&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today, we spend most of our time learning cues that predict secondary rewards like &lt;strong>money and fame, power and status, praise and approval, love and friendship, or a sense of personal satisfaction&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cravings are the second step, and they are the motivational force behind every habit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The third step is the response. The response is the actual habit you perform, which can take the form of a thought or an action&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If a particular action requires more physical or mental effort than you are willing to expend, then you won’t do it&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, the response delivers a reward. Rewards are the end goal of every habit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>​ Problem phase&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Cue: You wake up.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Craving: You want to feel alert.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Solution phase&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Response: You drink a cup of coffee.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Reward: You satisfy your craving to feel alert. Drinking coffee becomes associated with waking up.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>day06 Chapter 2 Summary</title><link>https://leoxiewl.github.io/2024/01/19/day06-atomic-habits/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://leoxiewl.github.io/2024/01/19/day06-atomic-habits/</guid><description>&lt;p>There are three levels of change: outcome change, process change,and identity change.The most effective way to change your habits is to focus not on what you want to achieve, but on who you wish to become.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Your identity emerges out of your habits. Every action is a vote for the type of person you wish to become.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Becoming the best version of yourself requires you to continuously edit your beliefs, and to upgrade and expand your identity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The real reason habits matter is not because they can get you better results (although they can do that), but because they can change your &lt;strong>beliefs&lt;/strong> about yourself.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>day05 Chapter 1 Summary</title><link>https://leoxiewl.github.io/2024/01/18/day05-atomic-habits/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://leoxiewl.github.io/2024/01/18/day05-atomic-habits/</guid><description>&lt;p>Habits are the compound interest of self-improvement. Getting 1 percent better every day counts for a lot in the long-run.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Habits are a double-edged sword. They can work for you or against you, which is why understanding the details is essential.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Small changes often appear to make no difference until you cross a critical threshold.The most powerful outcomes of any compounding process are delayed. You need to be patient.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An atomic habit is a little habit that is part of a larger system. Just as atoms are the building blocks of molecules, atomic habits are the building blocks of remarkable results.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you want better results, then forget about setting goals. Focus on your system instead.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You do not rise to the level of your goals. You fall to the level of your systems.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>day05 The most importantly, What is your identity.</title><link>https://leoxiewl.github.io/2024/01/18/day05-atomic-habits-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://leoxiewl.github.io/2024/01/18/day05-atomic-habits-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>THREE LAYERS OF BEHAVIOR CHANGE
&lt;img src="https://s11.ax1x.com/2024/01/18/pFADG9I.png" alt="pFADG9I.png" style="zoom: 20%;" />&lt;/p>
&lt;p>结果：The first layer is changing your outcome. &amp;mdash; losing weight, publishing a book, winning a championship.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>行动：The second layer is changing your process. &amp;mdash; developing a meditation practice&lt;/p>
&lt;p>角色：The third and deepest layer is changing your identity. &amp;mdash; your worldview, your self-image&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Outcomes are about what you get. Processes are about what you do. Identity is about what you believe&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Story&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Imagine two people resisting a cigarette. When offered a smoke, the first person says, “No thanks. I’m trying to quit.” It sounds like a reasonable response, but this person still believes they are a smoker who is trying to be something else. They are hoping their behavior will change while carrying around the same beliefs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The second person declines by saying, “No thanks. I’m not a smoker.”It’s a small difference, but this statement signals a shift in identity. Smoking was part of their former life, not their current one. They no longer identify as someone who smokes.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>When you have repeated a story to yourself for years, it is easy to slide into these mental grooves and accept them as a fact.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The goal is not to read a book, the goal is to become a reader.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The goal is not to run a marathon, the goal is to become a runner.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The goal is not to learn an instrument, the goal is to become a musician.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>THE TWO-STEP PROCESS TO CHANGING YOUR IDENTITY&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Decide the type of person you want to be.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Prove it to yourself with small wins.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>The most practical way to change who you are is to change what you do.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>day04 FORGET ABOUT GOALS, FOCUS ON SYSTEMS INSTEAD</title><link>https://leoxiewl.github.io/2024/01/17/day04-atomic-habits/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://leoxiewl.github.io/2024/01/17/day04-atomic-habits/</guid><description>&lt;p>Imagine that you have an ice cube sitting on the table in front of you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The room is cold and you can see your breath. It is currently twenty-five degrees.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ever so slowly, the room begins to heat up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Twenty-six degrees.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Twenty-seven.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Twenty-eight.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The ice cube is still sitting on the table in front of you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Twenty-nine degrees.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thirty.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thirty-one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Still, nothing has happened.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then, thirty-two degrees.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The ice begins to melt. A one-degree shift,seemingly no different from the temperature increases before it, has unlocked a huge change.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This is one of the core reasons why it is so hard to build habits that last.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Complaining about not achieving success despite working hard is like complaining about an ice cube not melting when you heated it from twenty-five to thirty-one degrees.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What we should do?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>FORGET ABOUT GOALS, FOCUS ON SYSTEMS INSTEAD&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Goals are about the results you want to achieve. Systems are about the processes that lead to those results.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>专注于要做的事情&lt;/strong>。&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>day03 Your future depends on what you do now</title><link>https://leoxiewl.github.io/2024/01/16/day03-atomic-habits/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://leoxiewl.github.io/2024/01/16/day03-atomic-habits/</guid><description>&lt;p>Habits are the compound interest of self-improvement.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>习惯是自我提升的复利&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They seem to make little difference on any given way and yet the impact they deliver over the months and years can be enormous.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>他们在一天内看不到什么区别，但是几个月几年时间的积累产生的影响可能是巨大的。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We often dismiss small changes because they don’t seem to matter very much in the moment. If you save a little money now, you’re still not a millionaire. If you go to the gym three days in a row, you’re still out of shape. If you study Mandarin for an hour tonight, you still haven’t learned the language. We make a few changes, but the results never seem to come quickly and so we slide back into our previous routines.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>我们经常忽略一些小的变化，因为它看起来没有那么重要。如果你现在省了一些钱，你不会是百万富翁。如果你去了三天健身房，你的身材仍旧走样。你一晚上学了一个小时普通话，还是不会这门语言。我们做了一些改变，但是结果并没有那么快来，所以我们又像往常一样。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A slight change in your daily habits can guide your life to a very different destination.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That said, it doesn’t matter how successful or unsuccessful you are right now. What matters is whether your habits are putting you on the path toward success.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>无所谓现在成不成功，重要的是你的习惯是否让你在通往成功的路上。&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>day02 1% better every day</title><link>https://leoxiewl.github.io/2024/01/15/day02-atomic-habits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://leoxiewl.github.io/2024/01/15/day02-atomic-habits/</guid><description>&lt;p>1% worse every day for one year. 0.99^365 = 00.03&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1% better every day for one year. 1.01^365 = 37.78&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://res.weread.qq.com/wrepub/CB_GbJ1U11UZEV96i36gZ6nmEpt_Image00004.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Photo by 1% worse and 1% better"
>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>day01 minor remarkable</title><link>https://leoxiewl.github.io/2024/01/14/day01-atomic-habits/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://leoxiewl.github.io/2024/01/14/day01-atomic-habits/</guid><description>&lt;p>Changes that seem small and unimportant at first will compound remarkable results if you are willing to stick with them for years. The pieces of things that are minor, but give you a sense of control over your life and you feel confident.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>