<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>English Daily on 林风's Blog</title><link>https://leoxiewl.github.io/english-daily/</link><description>Recent content in English Daily on 林风's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>zh-cn</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://leoxiewl.github.io/english-daily/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>day05 Chapter 1 Summary</title><link>https://leoxiewl.github.io/2024/01/18/day05-atomic-habits/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://leoxiewl.github.io/2024/01/18/day05-atomic-habits/</guid><description>&lt;p>Habits are the compound interest of self-improvement. Getting 1 percent better every day counts for a lot in the long-run.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Habits are a double-edged sword. They can work for you or against you, which is why understanding the details is essential.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Small changes often appear to make no difference until you cross a critical threshold.The most powerful outcomes of any compounding process are delayed. You need to be patient.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An atomic habit is a little habit that is part of a larger system. Just as atoms are the building blocks of molecules, atomic habits are the building blocks of remarkable results.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you want better results, then forget about setting goals. Focus on your system instead.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You do not rise to the level of your goals. You fall to the level of your systems.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>day05 The most importantly, What is your identity.</title><link>https://leoxiewl.github.io/2024/01/18/day05-atomic-habits-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://leoxiewl.github.io/2024/01/18/day05-atomic-habits-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>THREE LAYERS OF BEHAVIOR CHANGE
&lt;img src="https://s11.ax1x.com/2024/01/18/pFADG9I.png" alt="pFADG9I.png" style="zoom: 20%;" />&lt;/p>
&lt;p>结果：The first layer is changing your outcome. &amp;mdash; losing weight, publishing a book, winning a championship.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>行动：The second layer is changing your process. &amp;mdash; developing a meditation practice&lt;/p>
&lt;p>角色：The third and deepest layer is changing your identity. &amp;mdash; your worldview, your self-image&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Outcomes are about what you get. Processes are about what you do. Identity is about what you believe&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Story&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Imagine two people resisting a cigarette. When offered a smoke, the first person says, “No thanks. I’m trying to quit.” It sounds like a reasonable response, but this person still believes they are a smoker who is trying to be something else. They are hoping their behavior will change while carrying around the same beliefs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The second person declines by saying, “No thanks. I’m not a smoker.”It’s a small difference, but this statement signals a shift in identity. Smoking was part of their former life, not their current one. They no longer identify as someone who smokes.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>When you have repeated a story to yourself for years, it is easy to slide into these mental grooves and accept them as a fact.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The goal is not to read a book, the goal is to become a reader.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The goal is not to run a marathon, the goal is to become a runner.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The goal is not to learn an instrument, the goal is to become a musician.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>THE TWO-STEP PROCESS TO CHANGING YOUR IDENTITY&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>day04 FORGET ABOUT GOALS, FOCUS ON SYSTEMS INSTEAD</title><link>https://leoxiewl.github.io/2024/01/17/day04-atomic-habits/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://leoxiewl.github.io/2024/01/17/day04-atomic-habits/</guid><description>&lt;p>Imagine that you have an ice cube sitting on the table in front of you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The room is cold and you can see your breath. It is currently twenty-five degrees.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ever so slowly, the room begins to heat up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Twenty-six degrees.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Twenty-seven.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Twenty-eight.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The ice cube is still sitting on the table in front of you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Twenty-nine degrees.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thirty.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thirty-one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Still, nothing has happened.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then, thirty-two degrees.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The ice begins to melt. A one-degree shift,seemingly no different from the temperature increases before it, has unlocked a huge change.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This is one of the core reasons why it is so hard to build habits that last.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Complaining about not achieving success despite working hard is like complaining about an ice cube not melting when you heated it from twenty-five to thirty-one degrees.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What we should do?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>FORGET ABOUT GOALS, FOCUS ON SYSTEMS INSTEAD&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Goals are about the results you want to achieve. Systems are about the processes that lead to those results.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>专注于要做的事情&lt;/strong>。&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>day03 Your future depends on what you do now</title><link>https://leoxiewl.github.io/2024/01/16/day03-atomic-habits/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://leoxiewl.github.io/2024/01/16/day03-atomic-habits/</guid><description>&lt;p>Habits are the compound interest of self-improvement.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>习惯是自我提升的复利&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They seem to make little difference on any given way and yet the impact they deliver over the months and years can be enormous.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>他们在一天内看不到什么区别，但是几个月几年时间的积累产生的影响可能是巨大的。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We often dismiss small changes because they don’t seem to matter very much in the moment. If you save a little money now, you’re still not a millionaire. If you go to the gym three days in a row, you’re still out of shape. If you study Mandarin for an hour tonight, you still haven’t learned the language. We make a few changes, but the results never seem to come quickly and so we slide back into our previous routines.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>我们经常忽略一些小的变化，因为它看起来没有那么重要。如果你现在省了一些钱，你不会是百万富翁。如果你去了三天健身房，你的身材仍旧走样。你一晚上学了一个小时普通话，还是不会这门语言。我们做了一些改变，但是结果并没有那么快来，所以我们又像往常一样。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A slight change in your daily habits can guide your life to a very different destination.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That said, it doesn’t matter how successful or unsuccessful you are right now. What matters is whether your habits are putting you on the path toward success.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>无所谓现在成不成功，重要的是你的习惯是否让你在通往成功的路上。&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>day02 1% better every day</title><link>https://leoxiewl.github.io/2024/01/15/day02-atomic-habits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://leoxiewl.github.io/2024/01/15/day02-atomic-habits/</guid><description>&lt;p>1% worse every day for one year. 0.99^365 = 00.03&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1% better every day for one year. 1.01^365 = 37.78&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://res.weread.qq.com/wrepub/CB_GbJ1U11UZEV96i36gZ6nmEpt_Image00004.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Photo by 1% worse and 1% better"
>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>day01 minor remarkable</title><link>https://leoxiewl.github.io/2024/01/14/day01-atomic-habits/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://leoxiewl.github.io/2024/01/14/day01-atomic-habits/</guid><description>&lt;p>Changes that seem small and unimportant at first will compound remarkable results if you are willing to stick with them for years. The pieces of things that are minor, but give you a sense of control over your life and you feel confident.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>